# **Mritunjay Upadhyay**

An adaptable and responsible software engineer seeking a position in your firm which will utilize my technical skills along with organizing and communicational skills for the success of your organization.

Al Place, Wongthonglang Thailand (+66) 632467130

mupadhyay00@gmail.com

# **Personal Statement**

I am dedicated to developing and optimizing interactive, user-friendly, and feature-rich websites. I am a methodological, organized, self-learner. I leverage analytical skills and put strong attention to detail in order to deliver original and efficient web solutions, provide technical knowledge and expertise, and build new websites from start to finish.

# **Technologies:**

Languages/ Technologies comfortable: Aws, TypeScript, Node, React, Docker

Js: React, Redux, Meteor, NestJS,, expressJs, TypeScript

**Database:** PostgreSQL, MongoDB **OS:** Ubuntu (preferred ) / Windows

I am not limited to only these technologies. I explore and self study new technologies and implement them.

## **EXPERIENCE**

September 2018 - Current

# BCHU GROUP, Bangkok— Full Stack Developer

Bchu Runway is Thailand's largest designer outfit online rental platform. My main responsibility was to develop, maintain and improve the technical area of the organization.

#### Accomplishments:

- 1. Reduced Website Load time by 40%, directly improving the sales by 300 % in the first 6 months.
- 2. Implemented NestJS for API projects that are scalable and strongly typed using typescript.
- 3. Implemented various Payment Gateway for the website and mobile app to improve the customer.
- 4. Developed an in-house inventory management application to improve the efficiency of the team.
- 5. Contributed to 9+ in house apps.
- 6. Refactored majority of the code directly improving the performance of the system.
- 7. Building and maintaining monitoring tools especially for cron jobs, scripts, etc

#### **Key Roles:**

- 1. Develop and manage the website with a customer base of more than 1 Million users.
- 2. Train NestJS, ReactJs, docker, continuous integration.
- 3. Administer servers, handle load balancing, backups, and code deployment.
- Actively participate and engage in the improvement of User interface and Experience (UI/UX).
- 5. Improve the internal workflow by understanding the issues faced by the other teams.

Website: bchurunway.com

Technologies used: Node, React, TypeScript, NestJs, Meteor, MongoDB, Mongoose, Docker.

### **Quadtrust Infotech**, Kolkata — Software Developer

July 2016- September 2018

- Core role was to develop customized Enterprise Resource (ERP) software solutions for clients. Web applications were built with ReactJS with Redux. Main technologies: Node, ReactJS, Redux, Redux Saga, Webpack.
- Involved in architecting the application (SAAS Mobile App Half Traveller) using React-Native and Ruby on Rails.
- Worked as Backend Developer in Error fixing software for transformer (Trafixsoft.com).
- Mentored and Trained teams in ReactJs and React-Native for frontend development.
- Made an android app for real time data-sharing using React-native and Firebase.
- Work for real time game of word-puzzle solving using React-Native and Firebase.

**Technologies used:** JavaScript (React), Redux, Redux Saga, Webpack, node, npm, yarn, HTML, CSS, Ruby n Rails REST API's.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Frontend Certification from Free Code Camp.
- Data visualization Certification from Free Code Camp.

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Information Technology,

2010 - 2014, MCKV Institute of Engineering,, Kolkata India

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name	•	Mritunjay Upadhyay
Language	:	English, Hindi, Bengali
Date of Birth	:	30th July 1993
Nationality	:	Indian
Github	:	https://github.com/mritunjayupadhyay